Jaime David

New York, NY.| 407-729-2506 | jaime.r.david01@gmail.com LinkedIn | Github | Medium Page | Portfolio Website

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Experienced in JavaScript based programming, proficient in React, HTML and CSS with a background as a Chef, Painter and Graphics Designer. Possess strong skills in Team building, Efficiency, Design, Communication and Organization that help tech industries have a fun and unstoppable driving force for creation and efficient delivery of beautiful quality products.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

JavaScript • React • HTML • CSS • Ruby • Ruby On Rails • Git • Adobe Photoshop •
 ReactNative • Firebase • SQL • PostgreSQL •

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

A(ME)ZON | FIREBASE DEPLOY | DEMO VIDEO

- A fully functioning 'Amazon.com' e-commerce website clone made with "Stripe" e-commerce for back end.
 - Implemented Stripe for a safe and full back end e-commerce payment feature.

React / FireBase / Javascript / HTML / CSS / Stripe / FireBase Auth .

MOODY | [IN PROGRESS] | DEMO VIDEO

- A mobile chat app that bridges the gap between plain text messages and the emotion behind messages by labeling/ color coding each message bubble.
- Used FireBase "Snapshot" feature to create real time instant rendering of new messages for the back end.
 ReactNative Expo / FireBaseAuth.

(ME)FLIX | FIREBASE DEPLOY | DEMO VIDEO

- A static homepage that renders data with my recreation of Netflix's front end design.
 - Utilized TMDB, an online API for movies to fetch the website's data.

React / Ruby On Rails / Javascript / HTML / CSS .

EXPERIENCE

SOHO GRAND HOTEL | NEW YORK, NY | SOUS CHEF

JANUARY 2020 - NOVEMBER 2020

- Helped revise the menu then trained the kitchen staff all the skills and techniques necessary for a smoother and fool proof procedures that optimized quality and quantity at same time for any busy service.
- Reworked all the recipes based on sales per day of the week then structured a to-do list schedule to maintain supply and quality for very high volume demand for a year round 24/7 operation.

ROXY HOTEL | NEW YORK, NY | SOUS CHEF

SEPTEMBER 2018 - DECEMBER 2019

- Directed and emphasized the communication between front and back of the house operations to ensure flawless shift operations.
- Introduced a new schedule to all brunch, dinner and overnight teams that they still use till this day to ensure a smooth transition in between busy shifts.

TAO ROYALTON HOTEL | NEW YORK, NY | HEAD CHEF

DECEMBER 2017 - SEPTEMBER 2018

- Created seasonal menus for each season for all 4 kitchens with interchangeable seasonal ingredients to maximize production while keeping the food cost very low.
- Introduced a storage system to keep the kitchen incredibly clean and organized while maximizing speed of service because of easy storage and accessibility. This also took care of all department of health requirements that kept our kitchen at an A grade systematically.

EDUCATION